The unforgettable true story of a UFC legend.
The Smashing Machine is a history, drama film directed by Benny Safdie.
In the late 1990s, up-and-coming mixed martial artist Mark Kerr
aspires to become the greatest fighter in the world.
However, he must also battle his opioid dependence and a
volatile relationship with his girlfriend Dawn.
Mark Kerr, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Dawn Staples, played by Emily Blunt.
Mark Coleman, played by Ryan Bader.
Bas Rutten, played by Bas Rutten.
Elizabeth Coleman, played by Lyndsey Gavin.
McKenzie Coleman, played by Zoe Kosovic.
The Smashing Machine is a 2025 American biographical sports drama film
written, directed, produced, and edited by Benny Safdie.
It stars Dwayne Johnson as former amateur wrestler and MMA fighter Mark Kerr, alongside Emily Blunt as Kerr's
girlfriend Dawn Staples, with Ryan Bader, Bas Rutten and Oleksandr Usyk in supporting roles.
The Smashing Machine premiered in the main competition of the 82nd Venice
International Film Festival on September 1, 2025, where it won the Silver Lion.
It was released in the United States by A24 on October 3 and received generally positive reviews
from critics, with Johnson and Blunt receiving acclaim for their performances.
The film was a box office bomb, grossing $21 million
against a $50 million production budget.
It was nominated for the Best Makeup and Hairstyling
Award at the 98th Academy Awards.
At the 83rd Golden Globe Awards, Johnson was nominated for Best Actor in a Motion Picture –
Drama and Blunt was nominated for Best Supporting Actress – Motion Picture.
The film explores themes of drug addiction, biography, based on
true story, mixed martial arts (mma), price of fame.
The tone is emotional.